Sean McDonnell

(267)-772-4490 • 2124 S 15th St. Philadelphia, PA 19145 • tua57246@temple.edu • http://sean-mcdonnell.com

PROFILE

29-year-old college graduate with extensive experience living, studying, and working abroad. High degree of digital literacy. Proficient with professional graphic design and productivity software across multiple operating systems. Wide ranging web development experience from conception to design, coding, deployment, and maintenance. Strong ability to adapt to new situations and work effectively with others. Articulate, organized, self-motivated, and detail oriented with a strong passion for acquiring knowledge and developing new skills.

EDUCATION

Temple University Japan Campus (Tokyo, Japan) 2009-2010

Bachelor of Arts (BA) degree in Asian Studies, Japanese Minor, Certificate of Specialization in Japanese

Graduation: December 2010

Temple University Main Campus (Philadelphia, PA) 2007-2009

Middlebury Japanese Language School (Middlebury, Vermont) 2010

Inter-University Center for Japanese Studies (Yokohama, Japan) 2012-2013

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Ink-it Digital, Philadelphia, PA

2015-Present

- Build and maintain a variety of websites using latest front and back end technologies (HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, Laravel), task runners, CMSs, version control and graphic design software. Extensive WordPress and e-commerce experience.
- Provide on-site and remote training sessions (WordPress, Magento, Drupal, HTML) and ongoing 1-on-1 support for clients.
- Create and maintain Mailchimp/Constant Contact email advertisement campaigns and manage client social media accounts to drive site traffic.
- Collaborate with design and marketing teams to establish brand identity and tailor website UI/UX for anticipated user base.
- · Attended design and development seminars on current e-commerce site design best practices for increasing sales.

Freelance Web Developer

Philadelphia, PA

2014-2015

- Built WordPress and static HTML sites from design to deployment including domain registration, hosting, SEO and security.
- Utilized a variety of WordPress themes and plugins to create attractive and responsive websites including blog, local business, and e-commerce sites.
- Provided training and ongoing site maintenance for clients.
- Created original art and logos for websites.

Assistant Language Teacher (ALT)

2013-2014

JET Program, Nyuzen, Japan

- Developed creative and engaging lesson plans based on required middle school English curriculum.
- Effectively utilized technology to enhance learning, taking advantage of student's growing computer literacy.
- Fostered curiosity by linking lesson content with popular media and student's personal interests.

HONORS & ACTIVITIES

- Dean's List of Distinguished Students, all semesters
- Graduated cum laude
- Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society member

- Recipient of Ellen Stover Northup Award for Academic Achievement
- Temple University Japan Campus Senior Year Achievement Scholarship
- Temple University East/West Club Event Coordinator

SKILLS & HOBBIES

- Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator/InDesign
- HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, PHP, Laravel, Gulp, Git
- Microsoft Office (PowerPoint, Word, Excel)

- Learning Node.js and React
- BMX, gymnastics, fitness
- Sewing and textile arts